<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CIICADA Lab</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on CIICADA Lab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 11:00:00 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://CIICADALab.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rijad Alisic's Talk on How Privacy Can Improve Security Against Data-Driven Attackers</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/rijadalisic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/rijadalisic/</guid><description>Title: How Privacy Can Improve Security Against Data-Driven Attackers
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 18 November, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: In this talk, we will discuss methods that can be used as a first line of defence from data-driven attacks on Cyber-Physical Systems (CPS).</description></item><item><title>Erik Weyer's Talk on State conditional filtering</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/erikweyer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/erikweyer/</guid><description>Title: State conditional filtering
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday 11 November, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: The Kalman Filter is a well-known method for estimating the state vector of a linear dynamical system.</description></item><item><title>Shawn Ge's Talk on Equivariant filter for discrete-time systems</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/shawnge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/shawnge/</guid><description>Title: Equivariant filter for discrete-time systems
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 4 November, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: The kinematics of many nonlinear systems, especially in the robotics field, admit a transitive Liegroup symmetry, which is useful in high performance observer design.</description></item><item><title>What does it mean to be modular?</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/modularitytalk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/modularitytalk/</guid><description>Oliver gave a talk in the seminar series on behavior trees in robotics entitled What does it mean to be modular?
For more details you can check out this publication:</description></item><item><title>Yuen-Man (Mandy) Pun's Talk on Error Bound for Target Tracking Based on Time-of-Arrival Measurements</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/mandypun/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/mandypun/</guid><description>Title: Error Bound for Target Tracking Based on Time-of-Arrival Measurements
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 28 October, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: Target tracking is a key enabling technology in many applications of multi-agent systems and wireless sensor networks, such as motion planning and surveillance.</description></item><item><title>Elena Petri's Talk on Hybrid techniques for state estimation: event-triggered observer design and observer performance improvement</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/elenapetri/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/elenapetri/</guid><description>Title: Hybrid techniques for state estimation: event-triggered observer design and observer performance improvement
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 21 October, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: While hybrid techniques have demonstrated their relevance and strength in a range of control problems, they have been much less exploited in the context of estimation.</description></item><item><title>Distributed Optimisation and Model Predictive Control for Smart Grid Applications</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/research/mpc_smartgrid/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/research/mpc_smartgrid/</guid><description>In this research stream we investigate distributed optimisation schemes embedded in model predictive control algorithms to mitigate these difficulties. In particular, we investigate the potential degree of freedom of small-scale distributed storage devices (such as batteries) and flexible loads in the grid.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://CIICADALab.github.io/research/mpc_smartgrid/featured.png"/></item><item><title>Mandy Pun joins CIICADA Lab</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/mandypun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/mandypun/</guid><description>Dr. Mandy Pun has joined us as a new postdoctoral researcher. She will be working on problems in the field of online optimisation.</description></item><item><title>Equivariant Filtering for State Estimation</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/research/eqf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/research/eqf/</guid><description>Our ongoing research into equivariant systems has yielded a range of state estimation algorithms for systems on Lie groups and homogeneous spaces. We develop the general framework of equivariant systems theory to yield generic observer designs such as the Equivariant Filter (EqF), which has been shown to outperform state-of-the-art alternatives in problems such as attitude estimation and Visual Inertial Odometry (VIO).</description></item><item><title>People</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/people/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/people/</guid><description>Faculty Members # Philipp Braun Christopher Kellett Robert Mahony STR Lab Tim Molloy Ian R. Petersen Elizabeth Ratnam Power Systems and Optimisation Lab Iman Shames Nan Yang Researchers # Postdoctoral and Research Fellows # Abhishek Bhardwaj Power Systems and Optimisation Lab Pieter van Goor STR Lab Nanduni Nimalsiri Power Systems and Optimisation Lab Yuen Man (Mandy) Pun Research Assistants # Oliver Biggar Rebecca Craine PhD, Masters, Honours and Undergraduate Students # PhD and Masters Students # Yitian Chen Shawn Ge STR Lab Matthew Hampsey STR Lab Norak Rin Power Systems and Optimisation Lab Zeinab Salehi Power Systems and Optimisation Lab Honours and Undergraduate Students # Angus Apps Adhitya Bidarkal Olivia Dry Visitors and Adjuncts # Kasra Khosoussi CSIRO Alumni and Emeriti # Brian D.</description></item></channel></rss>