<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CIICADA Lab</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on CIICADA Lab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 11:00:00 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://CIICADALab.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Jamie Freestone's talk on Philosophy, feedback, and representations</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/jamiefreestone/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/jamiefreestone/</guid><description>Title: Philosophy, feedback, and representations
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, June 3, 2023, Brian Anderson Seminar Room
Abstract: Many branches of philosophy, linguistics, and cognitive science have tackled the problem of mental representations: how can one part of the physical world - a brain - be about or represent some other part of the world?</description></item><item><title>Giovanni Sansavini's Talk on Engineering Energy Networks Facing Global Transition: From Predicting Cascading Failures to Optimizing System Safety</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/giovannsansavini/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/giovannsansavini/</guid><description>Title: Optimisation and control of distributed energy resources for power and voltage regulation in distribution networks
Time, Date, Location: 10:00, Thursday, June 1, 2023, Brian Anderson Seminar Room
Abstract: Aiming at a sustainable energy production and at securing their energy supply, many countries are about to transition from a fossil-dominated to a green energy mix encompassing sunlight, mechanical energy and heat together with fossil and synthetic fuels.</description></item><item><title>Wilhiam de Carvalho's Talk on Optimisation and control of distributed energy resources for power and voltage regulation in distribution networks</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/wilhiamdecarvalho/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/wilhiamdecarvalho/</guid><description>Title: Optimisation and control of distributed energy resources for power and voltage regulation in distribution networks
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, May 19, 2023, Zoom Link
Abstract: While the adoption of solar power, battery storage and electric vehicles continues to grow worldwide, both technical challenges and opportunities emerge in electricity networks.</description></item><item><title>Shuixin Xiao's Talk on Quantum detector tomography: analytical algorithm, optimal design and regularization</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/shuixinxiao/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/shuixinxiao/</guid><description>Title: Quantum detector tomography: analytical algorithm, optimal design and regularization
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, May 12, 2023, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: Quantum detector tomography (QDT) is a fundamental technique used for calibrating quantum devices and performing various quantum engineering tasks.</description></item><item><title>Matthew Hampsey's Talk on Nonlinear trajectory tracking on homogeneous spaces</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/matthewhampsey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/matthewhampsey/</guid><description>Title: Nonlinear trajectory tracking on homogeneous spaces
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 14 April, 2023, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: Accurate tracking of planned trajectories in the presence of perturbations is a fundamental problem in control and robotics.</description></item><item><title>Jen Jen Chung's Talk on Perception, planning and learning for robot grasping and interaction</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/jenjenchung/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/jenjenchung/</guid><description>Title: Perception, planning and learning for robot grasping and interaction
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 31 March, 2023, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: The tremendous potential offered by robotic automation has been evidenced by its revolution of large scale manufacturing, mining, and agriculture.</description></item><item><title>Sofia McLeod's Talk on Globally Optimal Event-Based Divergence Estimation for Ventral Landing</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/sofiamcleod/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 14:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/sofiamcleod/</guid><description>Title: Globally Optimal Event-Based Divergence Estimation for Ventral Landing
Time, Date, Location: 14:00, Thursday, 23 March, 2023, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: Event sensing is a major component in bio-inspired flight guidance and control systems.</description></item><item><title>Kanghong Shi's Talk on Necessary and Sufficient Conditions for State Feedback Equivalence to Negative Imaginary Systems</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/kanghongshi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/kanghongshi/</guid><description>Title: Necessary and Sufficient Conditions for State Feedback Equivalence to Negative Imaginary Systems
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 24 February, 2023, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: We present necessary and sufficient conditions under which a linear time-invariant (LTI) system is state feedback equivalent to a negative imaginary (NI) system.</description></item><item><title>Iman Shames' Talk on Games as Graphs</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/imanshames/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/imanshames/</guid><description>Title: Games as Graphs
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 17 February, 2023, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: In this talk we re-examine the utility foundations of game theory. We present a simple and intuitive model of a game defined precisely by each player&amp;rsquo;s preference orders of their strategies, given the strategies of the other players.</description></item><item><title>Shawn Ge's Talk on Equivariant Observer Design for Discrete-time Systems</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/shawnge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/shawnge/</guid><description>Title: Equivariant Observer Design for Discrete-time Systems
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 10 February, 2023, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: State observer design for nonlinear systems is a key field in control theories.</description></item><item><title>Yitian Chen's Talk on Regret Analysis of Online LQR Control via Trajectory Prediction and Tracking</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/yitianchen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/yitianchen/</guid><description>Title: Regret Analysis of Online LQR Control via Trajectory Prediction and Tracking
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 3 February, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: In this paper, we propose and analyse a new method for online linear quadratic regulator (LQR) control with a priori unknown time-varying cost matrices.</description></item><item><title>Hyungbo Shim's Talk on Analysis and Synthesis of Heterogeneous Multi-agent System via Blended Dynamics Approach</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/hyungboshim/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/hyungboshim/</guid><description>Title: Analysis and Synthesis of Heterogeneous Multi-agent System via Blended Dynamics Approach
Time, Date, Location: 10:00, Friday, 3 February, 2023, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: This talk emphasizes that a group of heterogeneous multi-agent dynamics exhibits an emergence of new behavior when some parts of the dynamics are enforced to synchronize, and the new behavior can be represented by the so-called blended dynamics.</description></item><item><title>Vincent Liu's talk on An Introduction to Max-Plus Algebra and its Application to Optimal Control Problems</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/vincentliu/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/vincentliu/</guid><description>Title: An Introduction to Max-Plus Algebra and its Application to Optimal Control Problems
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 13 January, 2023, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: Control, estimation, and system identification of nonlinear systems continues to be a challenging problem owing to a lack of structure imposed by most problem settings.</description></item><item><title>Manuel Schallar's talk on Structure-exploiting optimal control of port-Hamiltonian systems and Karl Worthmann's talk on Model predictive control for systems with null-controllable homogeneous approximation</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/manuelschllarkarlworthmann/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/manuelschllarkarlworthmann/</guid><description>We have a double-bill.
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 9 January, 2023, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
The details are given below.
Title: Structure-exploiting optimal control of port-Hamiltonian systems
Abstract: We consider optimal control of port-Hamiltonian systems by minimizing the energy supplied via the ports.</description></item><item><title>Jochen Trumpf's talk on A Non-Linear Internal Model Principle for Observers</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/jochentrumpf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/jochentrumpf/</guid><description>Title: A Non-Linear Internal Model Principle for Observers
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 16 December, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: We show that any asymptotic observer for a non-linear kinematic system on a differentiable manifold contains a full internal model of the plant.</description></item><item><title>Pieter van Goor's Talk on Constructive Equivariant Observer Design for Inertial Velocity-Aided Attitude and Matthew Hampsey's Talk on Exploiting Symmetries for Trajectory Tracking Control</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/mh_pvg/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/mh_pvg/</guid><description>We have a double-bill.
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 9 December, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
The details are given below.
Title: Constructive Equivariant Observer Design for Inertial Velocity-Aided Attitude by Pieter van Goor</description></item><item><title>CSIRO's Robotics and Autonomous Systems Group's SubT and Beyond: Experiences at the DARPA Subterranean Challenge and Putting Robots to Work</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/csiro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 15:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/csiro/</guid><description>Title: SubT and Beyond: Experiences at the DARPA Subterranean Challenge and Putting Robots to Work
Time, Date, Location: 15:00, Wednesday, 7 December, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: he DARPA SubT Challenge concluded in September 2021, Team CSIRO Data61 placed second, securing 1 million USD for Australian robotics.</description></item><item><title>New book on “Introduction to Nonlinear Control” by Chris Kellett and Philipp Braun</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/nonlinbook/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/nonlinbook/</guid><description>The book “Introduction to Nonlinear Control: Stability, Control Design, and Estimation” by Chris Kellett and Philipp Braun can now be pre-ordered from Princeton University Press.
The book offers an introductory text on the analysis, control and estimation of nonlinear systems appropriate for advanced undergraduate and graduate students.</description></item><item><title>Rijad Alisic's Talk on How Privacy Can Improve Security Against Data-Driven Attackers</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/rijadalisic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/rijadalisic/</guid><description>Title: How Privacy Can Improve Security Against Data-Driven Attackers
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 18 November, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: In this talk, we will discuss methods that can be used as a first line of defence from data-driven attacks on Cyber-Physical Systems (CPS).</description></item><item><title>Inverse Optimal Control and Inverse Dynamic Game Theory</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/research/inverse_opt/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/research/inverse_opt/</guid><description>We are conducting research that seeks to enable engineered systems to infer the criteria of optimality underlying the actions and decisions of experts. This research has thus far explored fundamental theory and practical algorithms for studying the mid-air collision avoidance behaviour of birds, the driving behaviour of humans, and the decisions of players in competition and conflict.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://CIICADALab.github.io/research/inverse_opt/featured.png"/></item><item><title>National Electricity Grid Security and Resilience Facility</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/lief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/lief/</guid><description>Our project led by Dr. Liz Ratnam has been successful in the latest ARC Linkage Infrastructure, Equipment and Facilities (LIEF) round. The project is the result of successful collaboration between academics from ANU, the University of Sydney, and the University of Newcastle.</description></item><item><title>Erik Weyer's Talk on State conditional filtering</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/erikweyer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/erikweyer/</guid><description>Title: State conditional filtering
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday 11 November, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: The Kalman Filter is a well-known method for estimating the state vector of a linear dynamical system.</description></item><item><title>What does it mean to be modular?</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/modularitytalk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/modularitytalk/</guid><description>Oliver gave a talk in the seminar series on behavior trees in robotics entitled What does it mean to be modular?
For more details you can check out this publication:</description></item><item><title>Yuen-Man (Mandy) Pun's Talk on Error Bound for Target Tracking Based on Time-of-Arrival Measurements</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/mandypun/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/mandypun/</guid><description>Title: Error Bound for Target Tracking Based on Time-of-Arrival Measurements
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 28 October, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: Target tracking is a key enabling technology in many applications of multi-agent systems and wireless sensor networks, such as motion planning and surveillance.</description></item><item><title>Elena Petri's Talk on Hybrid techniques for state estimation: event-triggered observer design and observer performance improvement</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/elenapetri/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/elenapetri/</guid><description>Title: Hybrid techniques for state estimation: event-triggered observer design and observer performance improvement
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 21 October, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: While hybrid techniques have demonstrated their relevance and strength in a range of control problems, they have been much less exploited in the context of estimation.</description></item><item><title>Distributed Optimisation and Model Predictive Control for Smart Grid Applications</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/research/mpc_smartgrid/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/research/mpc_smartgrid/</guid><description>In this research stream we investigate distributed optimisation schemes embedded in model predictive control algorithms to mitigate these difficulties. In particular, we investigate the potential degree of freedom of small-scale distributed storage devices (such as batteries) and flexible loads in the grid.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://CIICADALab.github.io/research/mpc_smartgrid/featured.png"/></item><item><title>Perception, Decision, and Control in Uncertain Nonlinear Autonomous Systems with Safety Guarantees</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/research/safe_motion/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/research/safe_motion/</guid><description>In this research stream we focus on developing an integrated perception, decision, and control framework for a novel autonomy stack that incorporates the inherent uncertainties and nonlinearities of robotic systems.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://CIICADALab.github.io/research/safe_motion/featured.png"/></item><item><title>Stability, safety, obstacle avoidance and robustness: Analysis and controller design using nonsmooth Lyapunov functions and hybrid systems</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/research/lyapunov/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/research/lyapunov/</guid><description>Even after more than 100 years, Lyapunov methods still are one of the main tools in the controller design and in the stability analysis of dynamical systems. In recent years the focus has shifted from stability to safety and obstacle avoidance.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://CIICADALab.github.io/research/lyapunov/featured.png"/></item><item><title>Mandy Pun joins CIICADA Lab</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/mandypun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/mandypun/</guid><description>Dr. Mandy Pun has joined us as a new postdoctoral researcher. She will be working on problems in the field of online optimisation.</description></item><item><title>Equivariant Filtering for State Estimation</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/research/eqf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/research/eqf/</guid><description>Our ongoing research into equivariant systems has yielded a range of state estimation algorithms for systems on Lie groups and homogeneous spaces. We develop the general framework of equivariant systems theory to yield generic observer designs such as the Equivariant Filter (EqF), which has been shown to outperform state-of-the-art alternatives in problems such as attitude estimation and Visual Inertial Odometry (VIO).</description></item><item><title>People</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/people/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/people/</guid><description>Faculty Members # Philipp Braun Christopher Kellett Robert Mahony STR Lab Tim Molloy Ian R. Petersen Elizabeth Ratnam Power Systems and Optimisation Lab Iman Shames Nan Yang Researchers # Senior Research Fellows # Igor Vladimirov Postdoctoral and Research Fellows # Abhishek Bhardwaj Power Systems and Optimisation Lab Pieter van Goor STR Lab Nanduni Nimalsiri Power Systems and Optimisation Lab Yuen Man (Mandy) Pun Research Assistants # Oliver Biggar Rebecca Craine PhD, Masters, Honours and Undergraduate Students # PhD, MPhil, and Masters Students # Rudra Bhattacharya Yitian Chen Shawn Ge STR Lab Matthew Hampsey STR Lab Yun-Yan Lee Norak Rin Power Systems and Optimisation Lab Zeinab Salehi Power Systems and Optimisation Lab Kanghong Shi Rebbecca Thien Alex Wu Honours and Undergraduate Students # Angus Apps Adhitya Bidarkal Olivia Dry Visitors and Adjuncts # Kasra Khosoussi CSIRO Valeri Ougrinovski UNSW@Canberra Alumni and Emeriti # Brian D.</description></item></channel></rss>