<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CIICADA Lab</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/</link><description>Recent content on CIICADA Lab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 11:00:00 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pieter van Goor's Talk on Constructive Equivariant Observer Design for Inertial Velocity-Aided Attitude and Matthew Hampsey's Talk on Exploiting Symmetries for Trajectory Tracking Control</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/mh_pvg/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/mh_pvg/</guid><description>We have a double-bill.
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 9 December, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
The details are given below.
Title: Constructive Equivariant Observer Design for Inertial Velocity-Aided Attitude by Pieter van Goor</description></item><item><title>Jochen Trumpf's talk on A Non-Linear Internal Model Principle for Observers</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/jochentrumpf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/jochentrumpf/</guid><description>Title: A Non-Linear Internal Model Principle for Observers
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 16 December, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: We show that any asymptotic observer for a non-linear kinematic system on a differentiable manifold contains a full internal model of the plant.</description></item><item><title>CSIRO's Robotics and Autonomous Systems Group's SubT and Beyond: Experiences at the DARPA Subterranean Challenge and Putting Robots to Work</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/csiro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 15:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/csiro/</guid><description>Title: SubT and Beyond: Experiences at the DARPA Subterranean Challenge and Putting Robots to Work
Time, Date, Location: 15:00, Wednesday, 7 December, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: he DARPA SubT Challenge concluded in September 2021, Team CSIRO Data61 placed second, securing 1 million USD for Australian robotics.</description></item><item><title>Yitian Chen's Talk on Regret Analysis of Online LQR Control via Trajectory Prediction and Tracking</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/yitianchen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/yitianchen/</guid><description>Title: Regret Analysis of Online LQR Control via Trajectory Prediction and Tracking
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 29 November, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: In this paper, we propose and analyse a new method for online linear quadratic regulator (LQR) control with a priori unknown time-varying cost matrices.</description></item><item><title>Rijad Alisic's Talk on How Privacy Can Improve Security Against Data-Driven Attackers</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/rijadalisic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/rijadalisic/</guid><description>Title: How Privacy Can Improve Security Against Data-Driven Attackers
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 18 November, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: In this talk, we will discuss methods that can be used as a first line of defence from data-driven attacks on Cyber-Physical Systems (CPS).</description></item><item><title>Erik Weyer's Talk on State conditional filtering</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/erikweyer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/erikweyer/</guid><description>Title: State conditional filtering
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday 11 November, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: The Kalman Filter is a well-known method for estimating the state vector of a linear dynamical system.</description></item><item><title>Shawn Ge's Talk on Equivariant filter for discrete-time systems</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/shawnge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/shawnge/</guid><description>Title: Equivariant filter for discrete-time systems
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 4 November, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: The kinematics of many nonlinear systems, especially in the robotics field, admit a transitive Liegroup symmetry, which is useful in high performance observer design.</description></item><item><title>Yuen-Man (Mandy) Pun's Talk on Error Bound for Target Tracking Based on Time-of-Arrival Measurements</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/mandypun/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/mandypun/</guid><description>Title: Error Bound for Target Tracking Based on Time-of-Arrival Measurements
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 28 October, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: Target tracking is a key enabling technology in many applications of multi-agent systems and wireless sensor networks, such as motion planning and surveillance.</description></item><item><title>Elena Petri's Talk on Hybrid techniques for state estimation: event-triggered observer design and observer performance improvement</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/elenapetri/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/elenapetri/</guid><description>Title: Hybrid techniques for state estimation: event-triggered observer design and observer performance improvement
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 21 October, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: While hybrid techniques have demonstrated their relevance and strength in a range of control problems, they have been much less exploited in the context of estimation.</description></item></channel></rss>