<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CIICADA Lab</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/</link><description>Recent content on CIICADA Lab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 11:00:00 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Jen Jen Chung's Talk on Perception, planning and learning for robot grasping and interaction</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/jenjenchung/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/jenjenchung/</guid><description>Title: Perception, planning and learning for robot grasping and interaction
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 31 March, 2023, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: The tremendous potential offered by robotic automation has been evidenced by its revolution of large scale manufacturing, mining, and agriculture.</description></item><item><title>Sofia McLeod's Talk on Globally Optimal Event-Based Divergence Estimation for Ventral Landing</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/sofiamcleod/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 14:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/sofiamcleod/</guid><description>Title: Globally Optimal Event-Based Divergence Estimation for Ventral Landing
Time, Date, Location: 14:00, Thursday, 23 March, 2023, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: Event sensing is a major component in bio-inspired flight guidance and control systems.</description></item><item><title>Kanghong Shi's Talk on Necessary and Sufficient Conditions for State Feedback Equivalence to Negative Imaginary Systems</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/kanghongshi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/kanghongshi/</guid><description>Title: Necessary and Sufficient Conditions for State Feedback Equivalence to Negative Imaginary Systems
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 24 February, 2023, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: We present necessary and sufficient conditions under which a linear time-invariant (LTI) system is state feedback equivalent to a negative imaginary (NI) system.</description></item><item><title>Iman Shames' Talk on Games as Graphs</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/imanshames/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/imanshames/</guid><description>Title: Games as Graphs
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 17 February, 2023, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: In this talk we re-examine the utility foundations of game theory. We present a simple and intuitive model of a game defined precisely by each player&amp;rsquo;s preference orders of their strategies, given the strategies of the other players.</description></item><item><title>Shawn Ge's Talk on Equivariant Observer Design for Discrete-time Systems</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/shawnge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/shawnge/</guid><description>Title: Equivariant Observer Design for Discrete-time Systems
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 10 February, 2023, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: State observer design for nonlinear systems is a key field in control theories.</description></item><item><title>Yitian Chen's Talk on Regret Analysis of Online LQR Control via Trajectory Prediction and Tracking</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/yitianchen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/yitianchen/</guid><description>Title: Regret Analysis of Online LQR Control via Trajectory Prediction and Tracking
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 3 February, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: In this paper, we propose and analyse a new method for online linear quadratic regulator (LQR) control with a priori unknown time-varying cost matrices.</description></item><item><title>Hyungbo Shim's Talk on Analysis and Synthesis of Heterogeneous Multi-agent System via Blended Dynamics Approach</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/hyungboshim/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/hyungboshim/</guid><description>Title: Analysis and Synthesis of Heterogeneous Multi-agent System via Blended Dynamics Approach
Time, Date, Location: 10:00, Friday, 3 February, 2023, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: This talk emphasizes that a group of heterogeneous multi-agent dynamics exhibits an emergence of new behavior when some parts of the dynamics are enforced to synchronize, and the new behavior can be represented by the so-called blended dynamics.</description></item><item><title>Vincent Liu's talk on An Introduction to Max-Plus Algebra and its Application to Optimal Control Problems</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/vincentliu/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/vincentliu/</guid><description>Title: An Introduction to Max-Plus Algebra and its Application to Optimal Control Problems
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 13 January, 2023, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: Control, estimation, and system identification of nonlinear systems continues to be a challenging problem owing to a lack of structure imposed by most problem settings.</description></item><item><title>Manuel Schallar's talk on Structure-exploiting optimal control of port-Hamiltonian systems and Karl Worthmann's talk on Model predictive control for systems with null-controllable homogeneous approximation</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/manuelschllarkarlworthmann/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/manuelschllarkarlworthmann/</guid><description>We have a double-bill.
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 9 January, 2023, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
The details are given below.
Title: Structure-exploiting optimal control of port-Hamiltonian systems
Abstract: We consider optimal control of port-Hamiltonian systems by minimizing the energy supplied via the ports.</description></item><item><title>Jochen Trumpf's talk on A Non-Linear Internal Model Principle for Observers</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/jochentrumpf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/jochentrumpf/</guid><description>Title: A Non-Linear Internal Model Principle for Observers
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 16 December, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: We show that any asymptotic observer for a non-linear kinematic system on a differentiable manifold contains a full internal model of the plant.</description></item><item><title>Pieter van Goor's Talk on Constructive Equivariant Observer Design for Inertial Velocity-Aided Attitude and Matthew Hampsey's Talk on Exploiting Symmetries for Trajectory Tracking Control</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/mh_pvg/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/mh_pvg/</guid><description>We have a double-bill.
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 9 December, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
The details are given below.
Title: Constructive Equivariant Observer Design for Inertial Velocity-Aided Attitude by Pieter van Goor</description></item><item><title>CSIRO's Robotics and Autonomous Systems Group's SubT and Beyond: Experiences at the DARPA Subterranean Challenge and Putting Robots to Work</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/csiro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 15:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/csiro/</guid><description>Title: SubT and Beyond: Experiences at the DARPA Subterranean Challenge and Putting Robots to Work
Time, Date, Location: 15:00, Wednesday, 7 December, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: he DARPA SubT Challenge concluded in September 2021, Team CSIRO Data61 placed second, securing 1 million USD for Australian robotics.</description></item><item><title>Rijad Alisic's Talk on How Privacy Can Improve Security Against Data-Driven Attackers</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/rijadalisic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/rijadalisic/</guid><description>Title: How Privacy Can Improve Security Against Data-Driven Attackers
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 18 November, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: In this talk, we will discuss methods that can be used as a first line of defence from data-driven attacks on Cyber-Physical Systems (CPS).</description></item><item><title>Erik Weyer's Talk on State conditional filtering</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/erikweyer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/erikweyer/</guid><description>Title: State conditional filtering
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday 11 November, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: The Kalman Filter is a well-known method for estimating the state vector of a linear dynamical system.</description></item><item><title>Yuen-Man (Mandy) Pun's Talk on Error Bound for Target Tracking Based on Time-of-Arrival Measurements</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/mandypun/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/mandypun/</guid><description>Title: Error Bound for Target Tracking Based on Time-of-Arrival Measurements
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 28 October, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: Target tracking is a key enabling technology in many applications of multi-agent systems and wireless sensor networks, such as motion planning and surveillance.</description></item><item><title>Elena Petri's Talk on Hybrid techniques for state estimation: event-triggered observer design and observer performance improvement</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/elenapetri/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/seminars/elenapetri/</guid><description>Title: Hybrid techniques for state estimation: event-triggered observer design and observer performance improvement
Time, Date, Location: 11:00, Friday, 21 October, 2022, Brian Anderson Building Seminar Room
Abstract: While hybrid techniques have demonstrated their relevance and strength in a range of control problems, they have been much less exploited in the context of estimation.</description></item></channel></rss>