<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News on CIICADA Lab</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/</link><description>Recent content in News on CIICADA Lab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© 2024</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Workshop on Decision and Control</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/workshopdecisioncontrol/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/workshopdecisioncontrol/</guid><description>Location: Innovation Space, Room 2.04, Level 2, Birch Building, ANU Campus
Day 1, April 4, 2024 # Time Speaker Title 0845 &amp;ndash; 0900 Coffee and Welcome 0900 &amp;ndash; 0930 Ian Petersen (ANU) TBC 0930 &amp;ndash; 1000 Peter Dower (UniMelb) TBC 1000 &amp;ndash; 1030 Wynita Griggs (Monash) Unique Ergodicity in Feedback Control, and its application in Intelligent Transportation Systems 1030 &amp;ndash; 1045 Coffee Break 1045 &amp;ndash; 1115 Daniel Quevedo (QUT) TBC 1115 &amp;ndash; 1145 Mengbin Ye (Curtin) Adaptive-gain control of replicator dynamics in population games 1145 &amp;ndash; 1215 Tim Molloy (ANU) Extended Kalman Filtering for Online Discrete-Time Inverse Optimal Control 1215 &amp;ndash; 1330 Lunch Break (Not Provided) 1330 &amp;ndash; 1400 Robert Mahony (ANU) Symmetry in Systems and Control 1400 &amp;ndash; 1430 Mehdi Ghazavi Doezein (Monash) Frequency Control Analysis in PV-Rich Power Systems: A Dynamic Equivalence System Identification Approach 1430 &amp;ndash; 1500 Michael Cantoni (UniMelb) TBC 1500 &amp;ndash; 1515 Coffee Break 1515 &amp;ndash; 1545 Jie Bao (UNSW) On Data-Driven Control 1545 &amp;ndash; 1615 Rini Akmeliawati (Adelaide) TBC 1615 &amp;ndash; 1645 Philipp Braun (ANU) TBC Day 2, April 5, 2024 # Time Speaker Title 0845 &amp;ndash; 0900 Coffee 0900 &amp;ndash; 0930 Brian Anderson (ANU) Closed-loop near extremal optimal control 0930 &amp;ndash; 1000 Iven Mareels (Federation U) TBC 1000 &amp;ndash; 1030 Erik Weyer (UniMelb) TBC 1030 &amp;ndash; 1045 Coffee Break 1045 &amp;ndash; 1115 Jochen Trumpf (ANU) TBC 1115 &amp;ndash; 1145 Jason Ford (QUT) TBC 1145 &amp;ndash; 1215 Elizabeth Ratnam (ANU) TBC 1215 &amp;ndash; 1330 Lunch Break (Not Provided) 1330 &amp;ndash; 1400 Tal Shima (Technion) TBC 1400 &amp;ndash; 1430 Jasmin Martin (UQ) TBC 1430 &amp;ndash; 1500 Daoyi Dong (ANU) TBC 1500 &amp;ndash; 1515 Coffee Break 1515 &amp;ndash; 1545 Carlos Murguia (QUT) TBC 1545 &amp;ndash; 1615 Iman Shames (ANU) TBC 1615 &amp;ndash; 1630 Closing Remarks TBC</description></item><item><title>Outstanding Paper Award for The Attractor of the Replicator Dynamic in Zero-Sum Games by Biggar and Shames</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/altaward/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/altaward/</guid><description>The paper entitled &amp;ldquo;The Attractor of the Replicator Dynamic in Zero-Sum Games&amp;rdquo; by Oliver Biggar and Iman Shames was awarded the Outstanding Paper Award from The 35th International Conference on Algorithmic Learning Theory.</description></item><item><title>National Electricity Grid Security and Resilience Facility Launch</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/egsrlaunch/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/egsrlaunch/</guid><description>Our project led by Dr. Liz Ratnam has been successful in the latest ARC Linkage Infrastructure, Equipment and Facilities (LIEF) round. The project is the result of successful collaboration between academics from ANU, the University of Sydney, and the University of Newcastle.</description></item><item><title>Jamie Freestone, Amirali Farzin, and Maryam Khodababkhshloo join CIICADA Lab</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/newmembers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/newmembers/</guid><description>Dr. Jamie Freestone has joined us as a new postdoctoral researcher. He will be working on Philosophical Underpinnings of Feedback and Error Correction in Intelligent Systems. Amirali Farzin and Maryam Khodababkhshloo are our new PhD students and will be working on problems in the areas of online optimisation and decision making under uncertainty.</description></item><item><title>New book on “Introduction to Nonlinear Control” by Chris Kellett and Philipp Braun</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/nonlinbook/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/nonlinbook/</guid><description>The book “Introduction to Nonlinear Control: Stability, Control Design, and Estimation” by Chris Kellett and Philipp Braun can now be pre-ordered from Princeton University Press.
The book offers an introductory text on the analysis, control and estimation of nonlinear systems appropriate for advanced undergraduate and graduate students.</description></item><item><title>National Electricity Grid Security and Resilience Facility</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/lief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/lief/</guid><description>Our project led by Dr. Liz Ratnam has been successful in the latest ARC Linkage Infrastructure, Equipment and Facilities (LIEF) round. The project is the result of successful collaboration between academics from ANU, the University of Sydney, and the University of Newcastle.</description></item><item><title>What does it mean to be modular?</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/modularitytalk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/modularitytalk/</guid><description>Oliver gave a talk in the seminar series on behavior trees in robotics entitled What does it mean to be modular?
For more details you can check out this publication:</description></item><item><title>Mandy Pun joins CIICADA Lab</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/mandypun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/mandypun/</guid><description>Dr. Mandy Pun has joined us as a new postdoctoral researcher. She will be working on problems in the field of online optimisation.</description></item></channel></rss>