<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News on CIICADA Lab</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/</link><description>Recent content in News on CIICADA Lab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© 2024</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>National Electricity Grid Security and Resilience Facility Launch</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/egsrlaunch/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/egsrlaunch/</guid><description>Our project led by Dr. Liz Ratnam has been successful in the latest ARC Linkage Infrastructure, Equipment and Facilities (LIEF) round. The project is the result of successful collaboration between academics from ANU, the University of Sydney, and the University of Newcastle.</description></item><item><title>Jamie Freestone, Amirali Farzin, and Maryam Khodababkhshloo join CIICADA Lab</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/newmembers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/newmembers/</guid><description>Dr. Jamie Freestone has joined us as a new postdoctoral researcher. He will be working on Philosophical Underpinnings of Feedback and Error Correction in Intelligent Systems. Amirali Farzin and Maryam Khodababkhshloo are our new PhD students and will be working on problems in the areas of online optimisation and decision making under uncertainty.</description></item><item><title>New book on “Introduction to Nonlinear Control” by Chris Kellett and Philipp Braun</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/nonlinbook/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/nonlinbook/</guid><description>The book “Introduction to Nonlinear Control: Stability, Control Design, and Estimation” by Chris Kellett and Philipp Braun can now be pre-ordered from Princeton University Press.
The book offers an introductory text on the analysis, control and estimation of nonlinear systems appropriate for advanced undergraduate and graduate students.</description></item><item><title>National Electricity Grid Security and Resilience Facility</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/lief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/lief/</guid><description>Our project led by Dr. Liz Ratnam has been successful in the latest ARC Linkage Infrastructure, Equipment and Facilities (LIEF) round. The project is the result of successful collaboration between academics from ANU, the University of Sydney, and the University of Newcastle.</description></item><item><title>What does it mean to be modular?</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/modularitytalk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/modularitytalk/</guid><description>Oliver gave a talk in the seminar series on behavior trees in robotics entitled What does it mean to be modular?
For more details you can check out this publication:</description></item><item><title>Mandy Pun joins CIICADA Lab</title><link>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/mandypun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 11:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://CIICADALab.github.io/news/mandypun/</guid><description>Dr. Mandy Pun has joined us as a new postdoctoral researcher. She will be working on problems in the field of online optimisation.</description></item></channel></rss>